[KING OF COMEDY]
[Episode 4]
I'll pay you.
Okay.
You must be tired.
Take a break.
All right.
You too.
It's not like we're demanding to be paid.
Let me think it over.
Let's work on them a little more.
I'll try a different approach.
Weren't you a little too blunt,
bringing up money right off the bat?
Wasn't I telling the truth?
Sure, it's true, but you...
If that's the case,
you should tell her sooner
so she has time to prepare
instead of dragging it out as you do.
But the deadline isn't here yet.
What if it works?
I never really thought
this had a chance.
But things were looking pretty good
the last couple of days.
But today...
Let me tell you.
This job
wasn't worth taking in the first place.
We won't get the job done,
and we won't get paid, either.
She still has to pay us
every last cent.
How about we give them a discount?
What discount?
Discount...
I'm done talking to you.
I've got a call to return.
A debt collector?
Stay out of it.
Let me talk to him.
Give me the phone, and I'll talk to him...
Stay out of it!
Hello.
Mr. Chen?
Last time, you said
buying me out...
L-Let's talk about it again.
Mr. Zhou.
I'll let you get back to it.
I've seen you before.
Are you the planner Zhen hired?
What?
I happened to pass by once
and saw you filming.
And you are...
a thief?
Who's a thief?
Let me tell you.
I'm the village chief of this village.
Can a village chief steal?
Could a thief become village chief?
I was hungry.
I wanted some bread.
There was nobody in the store.
So I just grabbed some behind the counter.
Isn't that stealing?
Who's stealing?
Somebody help!
Stop yelling.
If you keep yelling, I'll...
The manager of this shop,
Chen Junnan, is my uncle.
I'm his nephew.
This is our family business.
At your age,
you have the nerve to call him your uncle?
Why not say he's your dad?
Sorry.
I may be old,
but I'm a generation younger than him.
You just make stuff up
and talk nonsense.
At your age... Somebody help!
Someone's robbing the shop!
Dehua. Dehua.
He's stealing.
The village chief's here.
Uncle Dehua,
you're back from fishing?
I'll let you get back to it.
I'm heading home.
All right.
Don't let me keep you.
Uncle Dehua?
See that?
So you really are the village chief?
You wouldn't have guessed, would you?
I didn't realize who I was dealing with.
I-I couldn't see clearly
with my glasses on.
I'm sorry.
My name is Zhou Ke.
I'm making videos for Zhen.
You're young and talented.
I'll keep my glasses on.
I can't handle bright light. (Also implies
someone who's done something shady.)
Can't handle it...
I'm sorry.
Pardon me. Sorry about that.
No, no, not at all.
By the way,
there's something I'd like to ask you.
Go ahead.
Pardon me, too.
From a professional standpoint,
gaining 100,000 followers in 7 days—
is this goal
achievable?
Professionally speaking...
Pardon me for asking, too.
Do you want it to work out or not?
If it works out,
of course I hope it does.
If it doesn't,
that's fine, too.
You've certainly covered all your bases.
No one else is listening here.
Chief,
let me be more direct.
Are you on Zhen's side,
or Chen Junnan's side?
I'm on the villagers' side.
What do you mean?
I can't dictate the villagers' choices.
But I have to give them choices.
That's a very broad perspective.
No wonder you're the village chief.
You said a lot without saying anything.
Those weren't actually my words.
Zhen's father said that.
Her dad?
Yes.
Zhen's dad was the former village chief.
I worked as his accountant back then.
The roads in our village
were all built during his time.
You know?
When he was alive?
Over 10 years ago,
he and his wife went out to sea
and never came back.
Zhen's really had it rough.
She raised Jiahao all by herself
and did everything for him.
She was both a mom and a dad to him.
I get why she's against demolition.
It's not because of the money
she put into renovating the house.
She's afraid that if the house
is demolished
and her parents come back one day,
they won't be able to find their home.
Zhen,
we're going fishing at sea again.
We're going farther out this time.
We might not be back for a week.
When we get back,
I'll make your favorite fish balls.
Zhen, take care of your brother.
He's too simple and trusting.
People can easily fool him.
I've left the money and bankbook
where they are.
Don't tell your brother.
Don't let him handle the money.
We're about to board.
Your mom left enough food for a few days.
Remember to eat.
Nephew of Junnan, please...
please stop crying.
So—
Zhen isn't with you?
No... no, she isn't.
I don't know where she went, either.
Let me tell you a secret.
If you can't find her sometime,
turn left when you leave
and follow the road to the end
until you see a utility pole.
Then turn right and go about a kilometer.
You'll see a lighthouse there.
She goes there whenever she's upset.
You'll find her there for sure.
From up here, our village
is so beautiful.
So beautiful.
How did you know I was here?
I didn't.
I was passing by.
The lighthouse led me here.
I want to be alone for a while.
Okay.
I said I want to be alone for a while.
Woof.
I'm not a person.
It's good.
Cola flavored.
My treat.
Let me tell you a story.
Once upon a time,
there was a kid
who loved acting from a young age.
He could sing and dance.
He could do it all.
He made up his mind
to become a great actor.
But sadly,
he was average-looking
and not tall enough.
His family and friends
thought his dream was a fantasy
and didn't support him.
But he ignored what everyone said
and took the entrance exam
for his dream film academy.
Sure enough, he didn't get in.
But here's the important part.
He didn't give up
retook the exam for 6 years,
and finally got into his dream school.
His dream of acting came true.
And today,
he's become an outstanding,
beloved,
and award-winning actor.
You're an award-winning actor?
I didn't mean me.
I meant Huang Bo.
His story is what inspired me
to work so hard to become an actor.
If I can become an actor,
what can't we accomplish?
I hope his story inspires you, too.
Don't lose heart.
No matter how hard the road ahead gets,
we still have to face it head-on.
We can take mountains
and rivers in stride.
We've still got a few days.
Let's think of something else.
You've still got me.
We can do this.
I've got a feeling
we can do this.
Just look at our beautiful village.
So beautiful.
Good village, good mountains,
good scenery, and good weather.
It's cloudy.
Well, not exactly.
It'll be beautiful when the sun comes out.
Cheers.
See? There it is.
The sun rises as always.
Dad, I know you love
doing crosstalk,
so
I had this custom silk robe
just made for you.
Does it fit?
Isn't it a little tight?
Not at all.
Slim-fit styles are in now.
That's how they dress at DEYUNSHE now.
Really?
Do you know why the collar is open?
Tell me.
So you can warm up your voice.
Oh, enough!
Just admit you bought it too small.
What's with all the bullshit?
You can't get anything right.
Come on, Dad.
Hear me out.
Don't call me Dad.
You divorced Yingying over a year ago.
I'm your former father-in-law at best.
If you couldn't
do crosstalk with me,
I'd have fired you long ago.
Do you know
why I've stayed for over a year?
I want to prove I'm capable
through my own hard work.
You know what?
I really want to get back together
with Yingying.
If you can't get
the Shapu Village job done,
forget about anything else.
If I can't get
the Shapu Village deal done,
I'll resign.
But if I get the Shapu Village
demolition deal done,
put in a good word for me
about me and Yingying.
All right.
What did you just call me?
Dad.
So that's what you were getting at?
Hello, Ms. Haidan.
Zhen.
Mr. Dehua.
Are you going fishing?
Yes, yes.
You're back, Zhen?
Zhen.
I-I want to buy a few things.
You go home first.
Okay. Hurry back.
Okay.
Mr. Chen.
Boss Chen.
Handsome Mr. Chen?
What handsome guy's looking for me?
It's my dear Mr. Zhou.
You're in a good mood.
Mr. Zhou.
Sit, sit, sit.
I just got back.
I came back as soon as you called.
Go ahead.
You've made up your mind
about buying you out?
I have.
I've decided...
I'm turning you down.
Pardon?
Stand up!
I came back as soon as you called.
Yes.
I didn't even get the supplies in town
and came straight back.
I haven't even eaten
or had any water,
and I had to wait, wait, wait...
only to get turned down by you?
Nice dancing.
I wanted to tell you in person.
That's how sincere I am.
It was good?
Yes.
But I don't appreciate the gesture.
What a shame.
Then I'll give you one back.
Get lost.
Goodbye.
Don't regret this.
Regretting it already?
I want to buy some water.
Get lost!
I can't even buy water?
Get lost! I'm not selling to you!
I'm not selling to you!
Ms. Zhen.
W-We still gotta eat, you know.
Right.
Let me get you one.
I'm using the other end
of my chopsticks.
At least have a few bites.
It's okay.
After talking things over today,
I think instead of trying things blindly,
we should go back
to using Yudan and Shengzai.
Right.
Let's think about
how to get them back together.
Right.
They have the best chemistry as a couple.
My cousin keeps telling me
-I really like them.
-she ships them.
Could we try talking Yudan into it?
We already tried.
Right.
Then let's talk to Shengzai.
There's nothing to talk him into.
Then let's do this.
Let's just...
You're close to her.
Let's go tell her.
Their relationship is one thing.
Work is work.
Keep them separate.
Have them put their feelings
aside for now.
Focus on the bigger picture.
Lots of divorced people in show business
still play couples.
It's perfectly normal.
Totally normal.
You're both here.
Jiahao.
You're having dinner?
You made fish balls?
Don't we eat this every day?
Give me 500 yuan.
500?
You're asking me for 500?
Do you know how much money that is?
Are you buying a house?
You two,
could you head upstairs first?
Okay.
Sit down!
What can't you say in front of us?
Obviously, I can't say it
in front of them.
If I could say it,
wouldn't I have said it
as soon as I walked in?
Do you know how much 500 yuan is?
And you're asking me for 500 yuan?
Can you stop lecturing me?
I'm out of options here.
I know He's probably having a hard time.
I'm already...
Do you know how much 500 yuan is?
500 is 5 one-hundreds.
I'm already tearing my hair out!
Do you know how many
fish balls I'd have to sell
I'll say it!
and how long it'd take me—
I was the woman hugging Shengzai
in the sugarcane field!
You?
That person I saw last night was you?
It was me.
Who are you kidding?
It really was me.
I dressed as a woman for a date.
You had to dress as a woman for a date?
The woman I was dating...
is kind of a special person.
Who?
Fang Hua?
What, you know her?
No.
Then why did you freak out like that?
Who is she?
The next village's chief.
I don't care if you're dating the chief
of the next village or our village chief.
Why are you asking me for 500 yuan?
Don't tell me...
We haven't gotten that far yet.
Oh, please.
You'll say anything for Shengzai.
I'm telling the truth.
That woman I saw yesterday...
Her feet were the only thing
that looked like yours.
She had long hair.
Where's your long hair?
Believe me now?
That's disgusting.
You even carry long hair around.
I brought it to explain everything to you.
But she was wearing a red coat, too.
Where's your red coat?
Well, I ran away, remember?
I ran down to the beach
and took it off.
And then...
Suddenly, a gust of wind came
and blew it away.
It blew away?
Yes. It flew away on its own.
Look at me.
I'm flying away, too.
I'm telling the truth.
Then go find the coat.
Why are you asking me for 500 yuan?
Let me finish.
Go on. I love hearing this stuff.
It's mine.
It's mine. It's mine.
500.
I don't have that kind of money.
W-Would 80 work?
500.
Give me 500.
Where'd you get the red coat?
I bought it.
How much?
80.
Where'd you get the money?
I saved up the allowance you gave me.
For 6 months.
I've been stuck eating 50-cent ice pops.
You want 500 from me.
80 for the outfit.
That's 580 altogether.
You made such a mess
of things for Yudan and Shengzai.
And you want 580 from me?
You made this whole mess
just because you wanted to date someone.
You really are good at messing things up.
And you still have the nerve
to ask me for 580?
How do you have the nerve
He didn't do it on purpose. It's okay.
It's not that much money.
We could cover it ourselves.
Right?
Thank you, Mr. Zhou.
It'll come out of your pay.
It's settled.
Thank you, Mr. Zhou.
Believe me now?
You're really disgusting.
What are you doing?
-I'm sorry.
-It wasn't me.
Give me a hug.
I'm sorry.
I know what happened now.
I was innocent.
I was so wronged.
I got violent.
You didn't call the cops, did you?
I almost did.
Oh, right.
I have a gift for you.
A stalk of sugarcane.
Don't...
So many people are watching.
Who's watching us?
It's just us in here isn't it?
Don't give up. Don't give up.
At least we solved one problem.
Even if we can't use the two of them,
at least we didn't cause them any harm.
Let's think of a B plan.
There must be another way.
I have someone in mind.
On the day we held the auditions,
lots of people came for the free eggs.
An old man told me
Yin Tinchiu was based on him.
Sir, go home and wait to hear from us.
Okay. Thank you.
Young lady.
What is this audition for?
"King of Comedy."
Sir, you've got quite a presence.
How about I give you a number
and let you try it too?
"King of Comedy'?
Is it that "King of Comedy"?
Yes.
What other "King of Comedy"
is there?
They didn't get it right back then.
You think you can get it right this time?
W-What do you mean?
He just wouldn't listen to me back then.
That's why it didn't turn out well.
Wouldn't listen to you?
Who? Stephen Chow?
Yeah, young Chow.
The Stephen you're talking about...
He came to our village back then
and lived with me for over a year.
He watched me every day
and based the movie on me.
Me.
So your surname is Yin?
My surname is Chen.
Chen Tinchiu?
Chen Xingwang.
Mr. Xingwang?
What's wrong with you?
Hey, hey, hey.
What are you doing?
What's wrong?
What's going on?
Do you know who he is?
Who?
He's Chen Junnan's dad.
He's obviously here to cause trouble.
He's Chen Junnan's dad?
But my sister says
he inspired the character Yin Tinchiu.
How is that possible?
I've never heard that in my whole life.
It happened before you were born.
What's that supposed to mean?
Let's look at this objectively.
Even if he's Chen Junnan's dad...
That doesn't mean they're alike.
Besides,
we don't have any other options right now.
We're running out of time.
What if he really is
the inspiration for Yin Tinchiu,
I hope he is too,
wouldn't that solve our problem?
Fine. But I don't trust him.
I trust you.
Trust me.
All right.
Let's go in and get to know him a little.
I'm not going.
Why?
He's been saying he wanted me
to marry his son
since I was little.
He's been going on
about it for over 10 years.
I don't want to see him.
Over 10 years? He's persistent.
Then go home.
I'll go talk to him.
Go on. Leave it to me.
Sir.
You're calling me "Sir" again?
That makes me sound old. Call me "bro."
Bro.
You said Yin Tinchiu was based on you?
If I may ask,
you weren't
sent by your son
to cause trouble, were you?
What did you say?
My son caused trouble for you?
He caused a whole lot of trouble.
Pretty Boy.
If you'd told me he was your son,
I wouldn't have added you on social media.
Who's Pretty Boy?
That's his social media name.
Nice. Playful.
I really didn't know about this.
I'll deal with him when I get home.
Could you give him another chance,
Little Dimples?
Who's Little Dimples?
That's my social media name.
I just changed it.
Sir, as for your son...
Go ahead and deal with him.
But you said
"King of Comedy" was based on you.
Well...
You don't believe me?
You don't believe it, either?
I'm on the fence.
So I wasted all afternoon talking to you.
It wasn't a total waste.
It's just that you
kept talking about eggs
the whole time that day.
So I...
Fine. Just wait.
I'll go get you some proof.
Remember to straighten
your son out.
Don't worry.
Pretty Boy.
He sure can spin a yarn.
Are you single?
I've got my eye on you.
Sir, I don't think we'd be a good match.
Don't get the wrong idea, dear.
I don't mean for me.
My son's single, too.
I think you two would be perfect together.
How about this?
Give me your contact info.
I'm Pretty Boy.
It's my social media number.
Take it.
I was pretty impressed
with you in the interview.
You were interviewing me?
[Life Album]
Look. Look.
Take a good look.
That's Stephen Chow.
Young Stephen insisted on a picture.
I didn't even want to pose with him.
Yeah.
You don't look too happy about it.
You look kind of reluctant.
You were so handsome when you were young.
Believe me now?
Well...
Well, bro...
You didn't Photoshop this, did you?
Watch your mouth.
You mean my photo is "P"?
("P" sounds like "crap" in Chinese.)
It's not that kind of "P."
It's, uh...
Never mind.
Bro.
Do you have any other proof?
I figured you might not believe me.
I've got even stronger proof.
This is... This...
This is...
Look. 200 Hong Kong dollars.
Look. Isn't that Hong Kong money?
It really is.
The year. Look at the year.
It's from 1994.
From 1994.
So what?
It's older than you.
Doesn't 1994 tell you something?
-Yes, yes.
-Think about it.
It does.
He stayed at my place for over a year.
Before he left, he asked me
if he could base a character on me
for a script he was writing
and paid me 200 for the rights.
I still haven't spent it.
So you agreed to it for just 200?
And 10 jins of eggs.
I get it.
Eggs really do the trick with you.
They're hard currency.
He also gave me 2 jins of pig ears.
That's quite a generous deal.
It sure is.
What do you think?
Better safe than sorry.
Bro, Yin Tinchiu was based on you.
-Right.
-We didn't recognize a big shot when we saw one.
-We're finally meeting the real deal.
-Our apologies.
Our apologies. Our apologies.
Well, bro...
In that case,
would you be willing
to appear in our video?
We'd like to show people
true story of the man
who inspired Yin Tinchiu.
Well...
We'll give you 10 jins of eggs.
And 2 jins of pig ears.
Well...
And another 200 yuan.
200 was fine back then.
But not anymore.
Then how much?
2000.
2000 won't do.
4000 minimum.
And no discounts.
Even then, I might not agree.
That's still not enough?
Then how about
I meet your son?
I'm not asking for more money.
Just meet my son.
Deal.
I watched "King of Comedy."
He didn't even invite me
to the premiere.
I watched a recording of it at home.
Was that supposed to be me?
He won the lottery.
It's the jackpot.
His son died.
Watching this is making me
squirm in my seat.
It's absolutely unbearable.
How did you act it out?
You won the lottery.
It's the jackpot.
Your son died.
See the difference?
Your head tilted the other way?
Next part.
I was watering a tree right here.
Young Stephen ran over and said,
"Don't move.
That's such a great pose.
Let me get a shot of you."
I stood here for 4 hours.
4 whole hours!
Then I saw the finished scene.
There was a girl standing
right in front of me.
So I was standing here watering a tree
while he was over here picking up a girl.
Stand here. Don't move.
See how it feels to stand here
for 4 hours.
Hey.
Can I just not work?
No.
Wait...
That's the original line.
But that's not what I said back then.
Young Stephen said...
Stephen Chow.
I mean, Director Chow said
that he felt so relaxed in our village
and didn't even want to go back
to work in Hong Kong.
I told him,
"If you don't go back to work
in Hong Kong,
how will you make money?
If nobody works, how can we make progress?
How can society develop if nobody works?
How will you afford pork head meat?
You know,
back in 1963,
my family finally managed
to buy a pig head,
and I didn't even get an ear."
Mr. Chen hold on...
Let's leave 1963 out of this for now.
Then what do you think would work?
You have to work.
You gotta work when it's time to work.
Work hard. Keep striving.
Good. That's good.
[Clip from the 1999 film King of Comedy]
Work hard!
Keep striving!
Okay. Here we go.
3, 2, 1, action!
No.
I can't yell that.
Why not?
What sane person stands facing the ocean
and yells out their innermost thoughts?
That's how it goes in the original.
Actors these days
are always shouting at mountains
or the ocean.
"Oh, mountains! Oh, ocean!
I want some pork head meat!"
Isn't that guy nuts?
Back then, young Stephen...
I gave him so many good ideas.
He wouldn't use any of them
and had to dig through the trash instead.
It pissed me off.
The more I talk, the madder I get.
My heart can't take it.
I need my pills.
Movies are doomed now.
Mr. Xingwang. Mr. Xingwang.
D-Don't get upset.
-Did you bring your pills?
-Bro.
How about we change the line?
Bro, don't get upset.
You can't shout, "Work hard!"
Get him a bottle of water first.
How about some eggs?
Back then, young Stephen...
I gave him so many good ideas.
He wouldn't use any of them
and had to dig through the trash instead.
Stand here
and see how it feels to stand here
for 4 hours.
Hey.
Can I just not work?
No.
All right. Get up.
Get up. Get up.
[2 Days Left]
Back then, young Stephen...
I gave him so many good ideas.
He wouldn't use any of them
and had to dig through the trash instead.
Hey.
Stand here. Don't move.
See how it feels to stand here
for 4 hours.
Mr. Zhou.
It's been so long.
Why haven't the numbers gone up at all?
With videos like this,
they need time to catch on.
It's a slow process.
Slow?
It feels like nothing's changed at all.
How about
we stop checking for now?
Don't worry.
Videos like this
usually take a little time.
Right. It takes time.
How long?
Sometimes it takes just a few minutes.
Right.
Other times...
Some videos don't take off
until a year or two later.
You never know.
That won't work.
Our deadline is tomorrow.
I-If we still don't
have 100,000 followers,
what do we do?
That's how the algorithm
works.
First, it shows your video
to a small audience.
If enough people watch it,
it gets shown to a larger audience.
If even more people watch it,
it gets pushed to an even larger audience.
Maybe our views
are growing slowly
because no one's watching.
Mr... Mr. Zhou.
Can you think of something?
I've got it.
We should try a different approach.
You could film me, for example.
Well...
You could film me fishing.
A lot of viewers these days
have never seen this kind of rural life.
They might be interested.
I could play a dog.
I often bark back and forth with the dog
at the entrance to our village.
A lot of people can't
even tell which one of us is the real dog.
How about filming me—
You could say I'm the inspiration
for Liu Piaopiao's character.
I could dress up as a woman again.
I've got experience, too.
Nobody could tell last time.
Jiahao. Jiahao.
Let me be honest with you.
In my experience,
if this video
hasn't taken off by now,
it'll be hard for more people
to see it anytime soon.
We might be running out of time.
It'll be tough.
Where are you going?
I'm going to see the village chief
and ask him for a few more days.
I'll go with you.
You two,
could you wait a few more days?
We'll go talk to the village chief
about it.
Is that okay?
Just wait a few more days.
I think that's fine.
We can stay a few more days.
We'll draw up an additional agreement
and charge separately
for the extra days.
Then we'll...
Please sit down first.
Both of you, sit down.
You sit down first.
Don't worry.
Well, we are worried.
This isn't about the money.
We can even waive our fee.
Don't waive the fee.
No, I mean...
This is really important to them.
This concerns your village
and your house.
I don't want to waste your time.
Even if you get 10 more days,
it probably won't make much difference.
So,
maybe you should
find someone else
and try another way.
I'm sorry.
We're screwed.
Jiahao, stop crying, stop crying.
Dad.
Stop looking at yourself.
Look at me.
What's there to look at?
Why are you making trouble?
Dad.
I-I'm at a crucial stage
in my career right now.
You won't help me,
but them?
Who else would I help but you?
If I weren't helping you,
would she agree to marry into our family?
She agreed?
It's pretty much a sure thing.
The rest is up to you,
so you'd better hurry.
Don't worry.
If she goes back to the Northeast,
it'll be too late.
Going back to the Northeast?
Who?
That chubby girl.
I...
I like Zhen.
Zhen.
What kind of taste do you have?
Zhen's no good for you.
Zhen
is always with that planner guy.
Feelings grow over time.
Sooner or later, they'll get together.
And you'll be heartbroken.
Listen to me.
That girl from the Northeast
is a great catch.
She bought me eggs
and pig ears.
Then I'll buy you some too, okay?
Just stop meddling.
Or I won't know
how to answer to Mr. Huang.
You can't answer to him?
Then how am I supposed
to answer to your mom?
Before she passed away,
she told me
Dad.
to get you married as soon as possible.
I know, I know, I know.
I, I...
I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
When you cover your face,
you can't tell
whether they're laughing or crying.
You think I can't handle you?
You little punk.
Mr. Zhou, Ms. Lin.
Thank you for your hard work.
Thanks for coming to our village
to help us.
Don't mention it.
Even though things didn't work out,
you still deserve credit
for all your hard work.
It's nothing. We're happy to help.
I'll pay you what we agreed on.
Oh, come on.
You're too kind.
We didn't come all this way just to...
Why don't you take it?
Me?
Yes. She's transferring it to you,
not me.
We didn't manage to help.